thompsoncigar.com 2017-03-13

# Privacy and Security

Effective November 17, 2015

## Privacy Policy Contents:

  1. What Information do you gather about me?
  2. How does Thompson Cigar keep track of me while I'm in your web site?
  3. Does Thompson Cigar use cookies?
  4. Communicating with Thompson Cigar via e-mail.
  5. How can I review the information you have for me?
  6. How does Thompson Cigar notify customers of changes to its privacy Policy?
  7. Is my credit card number secure?
  8. How do I know if a Web site is secure?
  9. An important note about debit and credit card transactions.

## 1\. "What information do you gather about me when I'm at your site and what do you do with it?"

The information we gather about you really depends upon what you do while you're at our site. Below are common activities and what we will ask of you.

Catalog Requests. We need a name and an address to send the catalog to. Plus a contact, either phone or e-mail, in case the address is wrong. To be removed from our mailing list at any time, call 800-216-7107.

Register to Win. We simply need an e-mail address and your home state.

Purchases. Your complete name, address, phone number, e-mail, and credit card information are necessary for purchase and delivery. Because most of our customers like to know that we received their order, we use your e-mail address to send you an order confirmation. We also use your e-mail address to let you know when we ship your order.

Because you have shown an interest in our products by registering, requesting a catalog or making a purchase, you may receive communications from us in the form of telephone contact, printed catalogs or e-mails with questions or information regarding orders you have placed and information about new products and services or upcoming events. If you do not wish to receive any or all of these communications, please let us know. You can contact us by e-mail, phone, fax or in writing. Please provide us with your exact name, address, e-mail and phone number and let us know which communications you would like halted.

From time to time, we exchange names, and other personal information with other companies whose products, and services might interest you, but only with your consent. If you do not want to have your name or other personal information shared with other companies, you can contact us by e-mail, phone, fax or in writing.

We may also collect information available from third parties, including address verification services, and may combine that information with information collected from you, including information you enter when you place an order, and information collected passively using cookies or similar technology, as discussed in Sections 2 and 3 below. We will use this information in order to fulfill your order, market our products, or to provide you with a better experience. 

We may from time to time contract with third party vendors to serve ads to our customers on our behalf across the Internet or to send our catalogs to customers whom we think may be interested in our products or services. To do this, the vendors will collect anonymous information about your visits to our Web site and your interaction with our products and services. This anonymous information is collected through the use of a cookie or pixel ta - industry standard technology used by most major Web sites. No personally identifiable information is collected during your visit to our website, which may include your name and mailing address, for purposes of determining whether you might be interested in receiving a catalog. 

## 2\. "Do you keep track of me as I move through the Thompson Cigar site?"

For each visitor to our web site, our web server automatically recognizes only the visitor's domain name. We collect domain names and aggregate information on what pages visitors access or view. Essentially, our web site is an online store. As such, in order to better serve our customers, we need to know which pages they view and how they get there.

## 3\. "Does Thompson Cigar use cookies?"

Like any business, we need to know the effectiveness of various marketing efforts. We use cookies to identify how a person came to and engaged with our site. This cookie contains absolutely no personal information about you. Cookies can be set with an expiration period. At Thompson Cigar, our cookies are set to expire after 90 days.

Accepting cookies through your web browser is your personal choice. You can set your browser to disable cookies. However, if you choose not to accept cookies, we may not be able to provide you with as good of an experience as one that is specifically tailored to your needs by utilizing the cookie.

Thompson Cigar permits sharing this anonymous visitor information with select marketing partners who may serve relevant advertising to you. You may opt out from this type of advertising by clicking here: [www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) Opting out of a network does not mean you will no longer receive online advertising from our about Thompson Cigar. It does mean that the network from which you opted out will no longer deliver ads tailored to your web preferences and usage patterns. We may also use technologies, such as our own cookies, to provide you with personalized online display advertising tailored to your interests. To opt out of our cookies used for this online advertising, [Click Here](http://dtmc.thompsoncigar.com/adinfo/choice/prod/?type=fpc&cid=3135&cname=ThompsonCigar&cmagic=8b8388&clogo=3135.png&loc=us&lang=en-us)

## 4\. Communicating with Thompson Cigar via e-mail.

We read every message that comes to us. We also try to respond back within 24 hours of receipt. We save messages and/or e-mail addresses only for a few specific reasons. We save messages if we think we'll need to refer to them later when we communicate with the customer. We do not use e-mail addresses that we receive through our Customer Service form, or from e-mails that we receive in correspondence directly from you, for the purpose of promotion, unless authorized to do so.

## 5\. "How can I review the information you have for me?"

If you created an online account, you may click on the 'Login' or 'My Account' link at the top of the page. There you will see the information you have supplied to us to place orders on our web site.

## 6\. "How does Thompson Cigar notify customers of changes to its privacy Policy?"

The current version of the Thompson Cigar privacy policy will always be posted here.

## Contact Information.

Business Address: 5401 Hangar Court, Tampa, FL 33634   
Mailing Address: P.O. Box 31273, Tampa, FL 33630-3303   
Fax: 813-882-4605   
Phone: 800-216-7017 

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to Customer Service.

We make sure that the information you supply to us remains secure and confidential.

If you don't find your question answered here, feel free to contact us by e-mail or phone 800-652-2948.

## 7\. Is my credit card number secure?

We use Secure Socket Layer (SSL) an industry standard encryption method to protect the private and personal information that you send to us through our web site. The encryption that we use on this web site is from GeoTrust, which is a leading provider of digital trust services that enable businesses and consumers to engage in commerce and communications with confidence.

Web browsers can operate in "normal" mode and in "secure" mode. You can tell which mode your browser is in by looking at the toolbar at the bottom of the browser window. If you see a broken key, or an open padlock, you are in normal mode. If the key is whole, or the padlock is closed, you are in "secure" mode.

## 8\. How do I know if a Web site is secure?

In order to be accurate, we're going to get a bit detailed here. When buying something on the Internet, there are three things to check for:

  * * Data you send is strongly encrypted.
  * * The site you're doing business with is the site you think it is.
  * * The site you're doing business with processes your credit card and address information in a safe and responsible manner.

Points 1 and 2 are taken care of by SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) and a Digital Certificate. A digital certificate contains the name of a company, Web site (like web name here) or individual, along with a cryptographic key that can be used to encrypt information that must be sent to that individual. When your browser switches into secure mode, it asks the Web site to present its certificate. The browser decides whether or not it trusts the certificate by looking at who issued it. If the browser trusts the certificate, then it will encrypt all communications with that Web site, using the cryptographic key in the certificate.

## 9\. An important note about debit and credit card transactions.

Your credit or debit card will not be charged until your item(s) is shipped, at which time we will email you tracking information. Before your item(s) is shipped, your debit or credit card statement will show what looks like a deduction from your account. Please note, these funds have not been deducted but are being reserved within your account to ensure your order can be processed. This is known as an "authorization hold" and typically lasts from 3-7 days (and may be longer), depending upon the policy of your bank.
